<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automate attention</title>
    <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Automate attention</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 09:09:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.brujordet.no/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Roelink cameras to play nice with the other kids</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/forcing_reolink_cameras_to_play_nice_with_the_other_kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 09:09:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/forcing_reolink_cameras_to_play_nice_with_the_other_kids/</guid>
      <description>So from my post about replacing my doorbell with a security camera you might have noticed that I have a accumulated quite a few PoE security cameras that I use with Frigate to get object detection and fancy integrations with Home-Assistant. The part I didn&amp;rsquo;t go into detail about was the struggle with my latest cameras, the [Reolink 820a](https://reolink.com/product/rlc-820a/].
So on the surface these cameras are great. They look nice, support power over Ethernet, doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on a cloud service and are very simple to set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing my doorbell with a security camera</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/replacing_my_doorbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:12:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/replacing_my_doorbell/</guid>
      <description>So my door bell ran out of battery, and I started wondering if I could use my security camera instead. In retrospect I could have gotten some batteries from the battery drawer, but where is the fun in that!?
So a while back I bought a bunch of Hikvision and Reolink Power over Ethernet (PoE) 4K security cameras. I like them because they only need one wire and have great quality builds for the price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using custom hardware in kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/using_custom_hardware_in_kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 08:55:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/using_custom_hardware_in_kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>One major difference between running k8s in a corporate setting vs running in a homelab is the extreme amount of custom hardware you end up wanting to put into the cluster. But this isn&amp;rsquo;t really how k8s was meant to be used. Any workload should be able to run anywhere, and be killed at any time and pop back up again. At least, for the most part. But I wanted to do some machine learning in my cluster using Google Coral TPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sniffing water out of thin air</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/sniffing_water_out_of_thin_air/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 08:59:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/sniffing_water_out_of_thin_air/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t like having to relying on other people&amp;rsquo;s computers, aka the cloud, so when I can I selfhost the tools and services I need. But sometimes there isn&amp;rsquo;t a service to selfhost. This was the case with my mysterious smart water meter which is now enforced by my municipality. After some research I found out that I might be able to get to my precious water data by using a radio dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who needs a homelab</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/who_needs_a_homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 10:13:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/who_needs_a_homelab/</guid>
      <description>In my second year at the Norwegian Tech &amp;amp; Natural Science University (NTNU) in Trondheim I joined DotKom. A subcommittee in the student organization which maintained the infrastructure and web services. One of the perks was that we were allowed to place one server in the University server room which had a gigabit internet line. Pretty amazing speeds in 2008. I was a poor student though, and didn&amp;rsquo;t have the cash to buy a server, so some of the more experienced DotKom members took me dumpster diving outside the various technical buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proper auto-completion for bash aliases</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/proper-autocompletion-for-bash-alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 09:58:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/proper-autocompletion-for-bash-alias/</guid>
      <description>Kevin in The Office once said &amp;lsquo;Why waste time say lot word when few word do trick&amp;rsquo;. These are words to live by, and this is why I love aliases. Lately though I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting really tired of writing out stuff like:
kubectl get pods -n network I was saying too many words. Step one was to start using contexts with kubectl which let&amp;rsquo;s me omit the -n network part. I used fzf to make a handy little function that would let me switch contexts quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking My Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/productivity/unlocking-my-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 21:27:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/productivity/unlocking-my-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Remapping caps lock to control and escape on Linux
The elephant on the keyboard Nothing good has ever come from pressing the CAPS LOCK key, either accidentally or intentionally during a heated discussion on IRC. As a long time user of Macbooks I&amp;rsquo;ve used Karabiner to improve the way my keyboard works. My most critical customization is to let the CAPS LOCK key die. Instead it will send escape if pressed alone, and control if pressed with any other key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a Simple Bash Prompt became a complicated problem</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/how-a-simple-bash-prompt-became-a-complicated-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 09:42:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/how-a-simple-bash-prompt-became-a-complicated-problem/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: This is a ´problem -&amp;gt; solution´ type post, reflecting on problems I encountered while writing a bash prompt generator.
 A small need for a more informative prompt This all started about 10 years ago when I was working as a Java consultant in Oslo. We had just moved from SVN to git, and the concept of feature branches was suddenly a thing. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really been very involved with VCS before git, but now I felt like I understood it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Delivery Platform</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/devops/building-a-delivery-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 20:28:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/devops/building-a-delivery-platform/</guid>
      <description>A journey begins Almost 10 years ago I finished my Masters degree in Computer Science and started working as a consultant at KnowIt in Oslo. My team was in charge of developing the integration bus for the local municipality, and we had earned a lot of freedom with the client. We ran our own Hudson build server, we were early adopters of self hosted Github enterprise, and we deployed to production at will using a suite of in house ruby scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor man&#39;s todo list</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/poor-mans-todo-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 10:45:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/poor-mans-todo-list/</guid>
      <description>I have two modes, completely distracted and dead focused. So naturally I need some help getting things done. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried expensive apps like Omnifocus, cli apps like Todo.txt or TaskWarrior and everything in between. In the end I realized that these apps are not for people like me. What works for me is big heavy tools for long term planning and collaboration like Jira or Trello. For my day to day stuff, the things I actually check regularly a simple checklist is more than enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I move faster around the shell?</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/how-can-i-move-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 13:48:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/how-can-i-move-faster/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m horrible at waiting, so when things are slow or repetitive I tend to automate them. So when I started working on my first Java project I quickly got fed up by navigating in and out of these crazy paths. For instance moving from src/main/java/com/example/application/package/ to the test path, or back to the root of the project got boring real quick.
function backto() { # Go back to folder in path local path=${PWD%/*} while [[ $path ]]; do if [[ &amp;#34;${path##*/}&amp;#34; == &amp;#34;$1&amp;#34; ]]; then cd &amp;#34;$path&amp;#34; || return 1 break else path=${path%/*} fi done } function _backto() { # completion for backto local cur dir all _get_comp_words_by_ref cur all=$(cut -c 2- &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;#34;${PWD%/*}&amp;#34; | tr &amp;#39;/&amp;#39; &amp;#39;\n&amp;#39;) if [[ -z &amp;#34;$cur&amp;#34; ]]; then COMPREPLY=( $( compgen -W &amp;#34;$all&amp;#34;) ) else COMPREPLY=( $(grep -i &amp;#34;^$cur&amp;#34; &amp;lt;(echo &amp;#34;${all}&amp;#34;) | sort -u) ) fi } complete -o nospace -F _backto backto The function backto and it&amp;rsquo;s auto completion counterpart, will let me chose one of the directories in my current path to jump back to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s going on in my shell?</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/whats-going-on-in-my-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 15:13:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/bash/whats-going-on-in-my-shell/</guid>
      <description>To help me figure this out, I use a few shell functions. Firstly, I need to know what configuration file that was used.
function shell_init_file() { # Returns what would be your initfile if [[ $- == *i* ]]; then echo ~/.bashrc elif [[ -f ~/.bash_profile ]]; then echo ~/.bash_profile elif [[ -f ~/.bash_login ]]; then echo ~/.bash_login elif [[ -f ~/.profile ]]; then echo ~/.profile else echo &amp;#34;Could not find any config files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 12:43:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Norwegian Software Engineer, weight lifter, hobby psychologist, metal head and I love to automate things. For the last few years I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping Tech companies implement DevOps best practices. At home I&amp;rsquo;m a husband, a dad and I build things for fun and not so much profit. I love working with Bash, so there will probably be a lot of that.
For this blog I&amp;rsquo;ll be keeping things short and to the point.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
