<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devops on Automate attention</title>
    <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/tags/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devops on Automate attention</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 08:46:57 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.brujordet.no/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I can&#39;t believe it&#39;s not dns</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/devops/i_cant_believe_its_not_dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 08:46:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/devops/i_cant_believe_its_not_dns/</guid>
      <description>A sudden urge to upgrade It was a warm spring day, kids were out of the house, I had just finished a round of Rocket League and I thought; Maybe I should upgrade my kubernetes cluster?
My homelab cluster is deployed using Kubespray which works by coordinating a myriad of Ansible scripts. It&amp;rsquo;s not the quickest solution, but it&amp;rsquo;s solid and customizable. These upgrades are usually quite uneventful, but I wanted to make some larger changes to how my gitops flow works, so I decided to just wipe everything after backing up all my volumes and start from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open a pull request to merge this engineer</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/devops/open_a_pull_request_to_merge_this_engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 08:00:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/devops/open_a_pull_request_to_merge_this_engineer/</guid>
      <description>The year of interviews A few years ago the company I worked for had a period of intense hiring. Over the course of a year I conducted at least 1-2 interviews pr week, so I ended up taking an active part in shaping our process.
My interviews were usually focused on technical skills for platform engineers or developers, and the main topic was often; &amp;ldquo;How do we know that they can code?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Delivery Platform</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/devops/building-a-delivery-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 20:28:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/devops/building-a-delivery-platform/</guid>
      <description>A journey begins Almost 10 years ago I finished my Masters degree in Computer Science and started working as a consultant at KnowIt in Oslo. My team was in charge of developing the integration bus for the local municipality, and we had earned a lot of freedom with the client. We ran our own Hudson build server, we were early adopters of self hosted Github enterprise, and we deployed to production at will using a suite of in house ruby scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
