<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iot on Automate attention</title>
    <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/tags/iot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iot on Automate attention</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 09:09:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.brujordet.no/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Roelink cameras to play nice with the other kids</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/forcing_reolink_cameras_to_play_nice_with_the_other_kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 09:09:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/forcing_reolink_cameras_to_play_nice_with_the_other_kids/</guid>
      <description>So from my post about replacing my doorbell with a security camera you might have noticed that I have a accumulated quite a few PoE security cameras that I use with Frigate to get object detection and fancy integrations with Home-Assistant. The part I didn&amp;rsquo;t go into detail about was the struggle with my latest cameras, the [Reolink 820a](https://reolink.com/product/rlc-820a/].
So on the surface these cameras are great. They look nice, support power over Ethernet, doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on a cloud service and are very simple to set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing my doorbell with a security camera</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/replacing_my_doorbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:12:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/replacing_my_doorbell/</guid>
      <description>So my door bell ran out of battery, and I started wondering if I could use my security camera instead. In retrospect I could have gotten some batteries from the battery drawer, but where is the fun in that!?
So a while back I bought a bunch of Hikvision and Reolink Power over Ethernet (PoE) 4K security cameras. I like them because they only need one wire and have great quality builds for the price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sniffing water out of thin air</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/sniffing_water_out_of_thin_air/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 08:59:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/sniffing_water_out_of_thin_air/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t like having to relying on other people&amp;rsquo;s computers, aka the cloud, so when I can I selfhost the tools and services I need. But sometimes there isn&amp;rsquo;t a service to selfhost. This was the case with my mysterious smart water meter which is now enforced by my municipality. After some research I found out that I might be able to get to my precious water data by using a radio dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
