<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>homelab on Automate attention</title>
    <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/categories/homelab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in homelab on Automate attention</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:12:01 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.brujordet.no/categories/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Replacing my doorbell with a security camera</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/replacing_my_doorbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:12:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/replacing_my_doorbell/</guid>
      <description>So my door bell ran out of battery, and I started wondering if I could use my security camera instead. In retrospect I could have gotten some batteries from the battery drawer, but where is the fun in that!?
So a while back I bought a bunch of Hikvision and Reolink Power over Ethernet (PoE) 4K security cameras. I like them because they only need one wire and have great quality builds for the price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using custom hardware in kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/using_custom_hardware_in_kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 08:55:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/using_custom_hardware_in_kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>One major difference between running k8s in a corporate setting vs running in a homelab is the extreme amount of custom hardware you end up wanting to put into the cluster. But this isn&amp;rsquo;t really how k8s was meant to be used. Any workload should be able to run anywhere, and be killed at any time and pop back up again. At least, for the most part. But I wanted to do some machine learning in my cluster using Google Coral TPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sniffing water out of thin air</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/sniffing_water_out_of_thin_air/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 08:59:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/sniffing_water_out_of_thin_air/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t like having to relying on other people&amp;rsquo;s computers, aka the cloud, so when I can I selfhost the tools and services I need. But sometimes there isn&amp;rsquo;t a service to selfhost. This was the case with my mysterious smart water meter which is now enforced by my municipality. After some research I found out that I might be able to get to my precious water data by using a radio dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who needs a homelab</title>
      <link>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/who_needs_a_homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 10:13:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brujordet.no/post/homelab/who_needs_a_homelab/</guid>
      <description>In my second year at the Norwegian Tech &amp;amp; Natural Science University (NTNU) in Trondheim I joined DotKom. A subcommittee in the student organization which maintained the infrastructure and web services. One of the perks was that we were allowed to place one server in the University server room which had a gigabit internet line. Pretty amazing speeds in 2008. I was a poor student though, and didn&amp;rsquo;t have the cash to buy a server, so some of the more experienced DotKom members took me dumpster diving outside the various technical buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
